[
  {
    "id": 1,
    "question": "The speaker failed to make the audience to __ him patiently. -Which of the following is the correct verb form in the blank above?",
    "options": ["Listen", "Listened", "Listening", "To listen"],
    "answer": "Listen"
  },
  {
    "id": 2,
    "question": "Which of the following ages in literary history is the latest?",
    "options": [
      "The Victorian Age",
      "The Augustan Age",
      "The Restoration Age",
      "The Georgian Age"
    ],
    "answer": "The Georgian Age"
  },
  {
    "id": 3,
    "question": "Wisdom শব্দের বাংলা অর্থ কি?",
    "options": ["মেধা", "প্রজ্ঞা", "বুদ্ধি", "জ্ঞান"],
    "answer": "প্রজ্ঞা"
  },
  {
    "id": 4,
    "question": "The first English Dictionary was compiled by ?",
    "options": [
      "Sir Thomas Browne",
      "Izaak Walton",
      "Samuel Butler",
      "Samuel Johnson"
    ],
    "answer": "Samuel Johnson"
  },
  {
    "id": 5,
    "question": "My uncle has three sons,-------- work in the same office",
    "options": ["They all", "All of whom", "Who all", "All of them"],
    "answer": "All of whom"
  },
  {
    "id": 6,
    "question": "People always remember patriots. -Which of the following is the best passive form of the above sentence?",
    "options": [
      "The patriots will always be remembered by people",
      "The patriots are always being remembered",
      "People are always remembered by the patriots",
      "The patriots are always remembered"
    ],
    "answer": "The patriots are always remembered"
  },
  {
    "id": 7,
    "question": "What is the meaning of the word ''Intrepid'?",
    "options": ["Arrogant", "Belligerent", "Fearless", "Questioning"],
    "answer": "Fearless"
  },
  {
    "id": 8,
    "question": "What is the meaning of the expression ''bottom line''?",
    "options": [
      "The final step",
      "The essential point",
      "The last line of a book",
      "The end of a road"
    ],
    "answer": "The essential point"
  },
  {
    "id": 9,
    "question": "The word ‘plurality’ means-",
    "options": [
      "The letter s",
      "Men and women",
      "The holding of more than one office at a time",
      "Chaos and confusion"
    ],
    "answer": "The holding of more than one office at a time"
  },
  {
    "id": 10,
    "question": "Paediatric related to the treatment of ?",
    "options": ["Children", "Adults", "Old people", "Women"],
    "answer": "Children"
  },
  {
    "id": 11,
    "question": "‘Bootleg’ means to-",
    "options": ["Smuggle", "Import", "Export", "Distribute"],
    "answer": "Smuggle"
  },
  {
    "id": 12,
    "question": "Are you doing anything special- the weekend fill in the gaps with the appropriate preposition.",
    "options": ["At", "On", "For", "In"],
    "answer": "At"
  },
  {
    "id": 13,
    "question": "WHICH OF THE FOLLOWING IS A CORRECT SENTENCE?",
    "options": [
      "HE WAS TOO CLEVER TO MISS THE POINT",
      "HE WAS TOO CLEVER TO GRASP THE POINT",
      "HE WAS SO CLEVER TO MISS THE POINT",
      "HE WAS TOO CLEVER NOT TO MISS THE POINT"
    ],
    "answer": "HE WAS TOO CLEVER TO MISS THE POINT"
  },
  {
    "id": 14,
    "question": "THE POET LAUREATE IS-",
    "options": [
      "THE BEST POET OF THE COUNTRY",
      "THE COURT PORT OF ENGLAND",
      "A WINNER OF THE NOBEL PRIZE IN POETRY",
      "A CLASSICAL POET"
    ],
    "answer": "THE BEST POET OF THE COUNTRY"
  },
  {
    "id": 15,
    "question": "WHICH OF THE FOLLOWING SCHOOL OF LITERARY WRITINGS IS CONNECTED WITH A MEDICAL THEORY?",
    "options": [
      "THEATER OF THE ABSURD",
      "COMEDY OF HUMOURS",
      "HEROIC TRAGEDY",
      "COMEDY OF MANNERS"
    ],
    "answer": "COMEDY OF HUMOURS"
  },
  {
    "id": 16,
    "question": "WHO OF THE FOLLOWING WAS BOTH A POET AND PAINTER?",
    "options": ["DONNE", "KEATS", "BLAKE", "SPENCER"],
    "answer": "BLAKE"
  },
  {
    "id": 17,
    "question": "What is the synonym of INCREDIBLE?",
    "options": ["UNTHINKABLE", "UNBELIEVABLE", "UNTHINKING", "UNLIKELY"],
    "answer": "UNBELIEVABLE"
  },
  {
    "id": 18,
    "question": "What is the antonym of FAMOUS?",
    "options": ["OBSCURE", "ILLITERATE", "OPAQUE", "IMMATURE"],
    "answer": "OBSCURE"
  },
  {
    "id": 19,
    "question": "PLEBISCITE IS A TERM RELATED TO-",
    "options": ["MEDICINE", "TECHNOLOGY", "LAW", "POLITICS"],
    "answer": "POLITICS"
  },
  {
    "id": 20,
    "question": "WHO WROTE BEAUTY IS TRUTH, TRUTH IS BEAUTY?",
    "options": ["SHAKESPEARE", "WORDSWORTH", "KEATS", "ELIOT"],
    "answer": "KEATS"
  },
  {
    "id": 21,
    "question": "MANY ISLANDS MAKE UP-",
    "options": ["AN ISLES", "AN ARCHIPELAGO", "A PENINSULA", "A CONTINENT"],
    "answer": "AN ARCHIPELAGO"
  }
]
